class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}
List<QuestionModel> soil_and_water_conversarion = [


  QuestionModel(question: "1. What is the primary purpose of soil conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase soil erosion",
        "B. Preserve soil fertility",
        "C. Reduce water infiltration",
        "D. Encourage desertification"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Soil conservation aims to preserve soil fertility by preventing erosion and maintaining the quality of the soil.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "2. Which of the following is a common soil conservation practice to prevent erosion on sloping lands?",
      options: [
        "A. Contour plowing",
        "B. Overgrazing",
        "C. Monoculture farming",
        "D. Deep plowing"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'Contour plowing involves plowing along the contour lines of the land, reducing the risk of water erosion on slopes.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "3. What is the role of cover crops in soil conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase evaporation",
        "B. Provide habitat for pests",
        "C. Protect soil from erosion",
        "D. Decrease soil fertility"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Cover crops protect the soil from erosion by providing a protective cover and enhancing soil structure.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "4. Which of the following is an example of water conservation in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Excessive irrigation",
        "B. Drip irrigation",
        "C. Open channel irrigation",
        "D. Flooding fields"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Drip irrigation is an efficient water conservation method that delivers water directly to the plant roots, minimizing water wastage.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "5. What is the purpose of contour bunding in soil conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase runoff",
        "B. Trap sediment and water",
        "C. Promote soil erosion",
        "D. Reduce soil fertility"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Contour bunding helps trap sediment and water, preventing soil erosion and promoting water conservation.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "6. How does afforestation contribute to soil conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increases soil erosion",
        "B. Reduces groundwater recharge",
        "C. Improves soil structure",
        "D. Encourages desertification"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Afforestation improves soil structure by adding organic matter, preventing erosion and enhancing water retention.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "7. Which of the following is a key factor in preventing soil erosion?",
      options: [
        "A. Deforestation",
        "B. Overgrazing",
        "C. Vegetative cover",
        "D. Deep plowing"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Maintaining vegetative cover is crucial in preventing soil erosion as it protects the soil from the impact of rainfall and wind.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "8. What is the purpose of a riparian buffer in water conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase water pollution",
        "B. Reduce water infiltration",
        "C. Filter pollutants and sediments",
        "D. Encourage streambank erosion"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'A riparian buffer helps filter pollutants and sediments, protecting water quality and preventing streambank erosion.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "9. How does contour trenching contribute to soil conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increases soil erosion",
        "B. Reduces water retention",
        "C. Slows down water runoff",
        "D. Promotes overland flow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Contour trenching slows down water runoff, allowing water to infiltrate the soil and reducing the risk of erosion.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "10. Which soil conservation practice involves alternating strips of crops or vegetation?",
      options: [
        "A. Monoculture",
        "B. Crop rotation",
        "C. Strip cropping",
        "D. No-till farming"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Strip cropping involves alternating strips of different crops or vegetation to reduce soil erosion and enhance biodiversity.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "11. What is the primary purpose of a check dam in water conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase water runoff",
        "B. Prevent sediment deposition",
        "C. Encourage streambank erosion",
        "D. Reduce water storage"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A check dam helps prevent sediment deposition by slowing down water flow, promoting sediment settlement.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "12. Which of the following practices is detrimental to soil conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Terracing",
        "B. Overgrazing",
        "C. Mulching",
        "D. Agroforestry"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Overgrazing can lead to soil degradation, reducing vegetative cover and increasing the risk of erosion.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "13. What is the primary goal of water harvesting in soil and water conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase surface runoff",
        "B. Recharge groundwater",
        "C. Promote water wastage",
        "D. Enhance soil erosion"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Water harvesting aims to recharge groundwater, contributing to sustainable water availability and soil moisture.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "14. How does no-till farming contribute to soil conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increases soil erosion",
        "B. Promotes soil compaction",
        "C. Enhances soil structure",
        "D. Encourages deforestation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'No-till farming enhances soil structure by reducing soil disturbance, preventing erosion, and preserving soil organic matter.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "15. What is the purpose of a windbreak in soil conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase wind erosion",
        "B. Reduce soil fertility",
        "C. Protect crops from wind damage",
        "D. Promote desertification"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'A windbreak protects crops from wind damage, reducing the risk of soil erosion and preserving soil fertility.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "16. Which of the following is a method of water conservation in urban areas?",
      options: [
        "A. Excessive lawn watering",
        "B. Rainwater harvesting",
        "C. Watering during peak hours",
        "D. Concrete paving"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Rainwater harvesting in urban areas helps conserve water by capturing and storing rainwater for later use.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "17. How does agroforestry contribute to soil and water conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increases soil erosion",
        "B. Reduces biodiversity",
        "C. Enhances water retention",
        "D. Promotes monoculture"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Agroforestry enhances water retention and biodiversity, reducing soil erosion and promoting sustainable land use.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "18. What is the primary purpose of contour bunding in soil conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase runoff",
        "B. Trap sediment and water",
        "C. Promote soil erosion",
        "D. Reduce soil fertility"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Contour bunding helps trap sediment and water, preventing soil erosion and promoting water conservation.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "19. How does the use of cover crops contribute to soil health?",
      options: [
        "A. Increases soil compaction",
        "B. Promotes soil erosion",
        "C. Adds organic matter and prevents erosion",
        "D. Decreases water infiltration"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Cover crops add organic matter to the soil, prevent erosion, and improve soil structure, contributing to overall soil health.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "20. What is the primary purpose of a check dam in water conservation?",
      options: [
        "A. Increase water runoff",
        "B. Prevent sediment deposition",
        "C. Encourage streambank erosion",
        "D. Reduce water storage"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A check dam helps prevent sediment deposition by slowing down water flow, promoting sediment settlement.'
  ),

  ];